所以我们的第一步是创建一个elixir项目
so our first step is to create an elixir project
并运行一些代码
and get some code running
毫不奇怪
and no surprise
elixir 有组织项目的约定和
elixir has conventions for organizing projects and
自动化项目任务的好工具
great tooling to automate project tasks
创建一个新的长生不老药项目
to create a new elixir project
我们使用我们所说的混合命令 mix new
we use the mix command that we say mix new
并且navar项目将会被看到
and the navar project is going to be see
它在那里生成了一些文件和目录
and it generated a few files and directories there
我们马上看看那些
we'll look at those in just a minute now
混合工具让我们自动化常见的项目任务
the mix tool lets us automate common project tasks
有点像 ruby 的 rake 工具
sort of like ruby's rake tool
实际上，如果您只想查看您所做的所有任务
in fact if you just want to see all the tasks you do
混合帮助，它列出了所有这些
mix help and it lists all those out
所以我们做了 mix new 来创建一个新的 elixir 项目
so we did the mix new to create a new elixir project
但是这里有很多任务
but there's a load of tasks in here for
只是你想做的普通事情
just common things you want to do
围绕你的长生不老药项目
around your elixir project
所以我只是要更改目录
so I'm just going to change directory
进入那个
into that
调查项目目录，然后在
survey project directory and then open it up in
我的编辑
my editor
让我们快速浏览一下轻量级
let's take a quick peek at the lightweight
目录结构
directory structure
混合新命令创建
that the mix new command created
我们有一个 con 目录
we've got a con directory
其中包含一个可配置的文件
which contains one file configurable
exs 和这个文件负责
exs and this file is responsible for
配置应用程序
configuring the application
这里不足为奇
no surprise here
大部分是评论和
most of it is comments and
你必须放弃的情况很少见
it's pretty rare that you have to drop
进入这个并改变任何东西
into this and change anything
我们会回到这个
we'll return back to this
因为我们稍后在课程中需要它
as we need it later on in the course
我们有一个实时目录
and we've got a live directory
这是我们的应用程序代码将要存在的地方
this is where our application code is going to live
并进行了调查
and generated a survey
ex 文件，我们将在稍后查看
ex file which we'll look at in just a second
我们还有一个测试目录，这并不奇怪
we also have a test directory which no surprise
在这些生成的测试中有一些测试
has some test inside of those some generated tests
我们稍后再看这些
again we'll look at those a little bit later
然后我们有这个混合exs
and then we have this mix exs
这就是我们配置项目的地方
and this is where we configure our project
及其依赖项
and its dependencies
我们必须添加
we'll have to add
稍后在课程中的依赖项
a dependency a little bit later on in the course
所以我们也会回到这个文件
so we'll come back to this file as well
现在不要让两个文件扩展名点
now don't let the two file extensions dot
ex 和 dot exs 把你扔了
ex and dot exs throw you
两种类型的文件都包含长生不老药代码
both types of files contain elixir code
dot ex 文件旨在编译然后运行
dot ex files are meant to be compiled and then run
而点性
whereas dot sex
文件像脚本一样被有效地解释
files are effectively interpreted like scripts
因此尾随 s
thus the trailing s
大多数时候，虽然你只会使用
most of the time though you'll just use the
扩展名
ex extension
这正是我们在这个塞尔维亚的延伸
and that's exactly the extension we have on this serbia
例如因为它是应用程序代码
ex because it's application code
我们所有的应用程序代码都会有一个
and all of our application code is going to have a
ex 扩展名，所以我将删除这些评论
ex extension so I'm just going to remove these comments
所以我们可以专注于代码
so we can focus on the code
并且长生不老药的代码总是组织在名称模块中
and elixir code is always organized in name module
所以文件首先在这里定义一个模块
so the file starts by defining a module here
这只是一个名字
which is just a name
它使用 def 模块的功能空间
space for functions it uses def module
然后看到模块的名称
then the name of the module is see
请注意它以大写字符开头
notice that it starts with an uppercase character
以及所有模块名称和长生不老药使用
and all module names and elixir use
骆驼案类似于
camel case similar to
ruby 类和模块
ruby classes and modules
然后在模块内部我们有一个
then inside of the module we have a
名称函数称为 hello
name function called hello
和
and
函数名是带下划线的小写或
the function names are lowercase with underscores or
蛇案例，这些类似于 ruby 方法名称
snake case and these are similar to ruby method names
和
and
所有名称函数都必须在模块内定义
all name functions must be defined inside of a module
如果你是一名 Ruby 程序员
if you're a ruby programmer
这应该看起来很熟悉
this should look fairly familiar
但一件事可能会让你绊倒
but one thing that might trip you up
至少我的一次旅行试图记住
that at least a trip to me up was trying to remember
打露水
to type the dew
是的
yeah
我总是忘记这些行尾的这些会费
I always forget these dues on the ends of these lines
所以这只是要记住的事情
so that's just something to keep in mind
这个 hello 函数当前正在返回一个
and this hello function is currently returning an
原子，就像红宝石中的符号
atom which is like a symbol in ruby
所以这是原子世界
so it's the atom world
而亚当只是一个
and adam is just a
值与其名称相同的名称或
name whose value is the same as its name or
一个常数
a constant
让它在这里返回一个适当的问候
let's just have it return a proper greeting here
所以我们将使用一个双引号的长生不老药字符串
so we'll use an elixir string which is double quotes
毫不奇怪，然后我们可以使用字符串插值
no surprise and then we can use string interpolation
就像在红宝石中一样
just like in ruby
如果我们想打招呼
if we wanted to say hello
一些名字，然后我们可以把这个名字传入
some name and then we could pass that name in
作为 hello 函数的参数
as an argument to the hello function
然后调用一个函数
then to call a function
我们要下来
we're going to come down
在这个模块之外，我将使用 io
outside of this module and I'm going to use io
这是一个内置在 elixir 中的模块名称
that's a module name that's built into elixir
使用看跌期权
use puts
如果您是 ruby 程序员，这应该很熟悉
which should be familiar if you're a ruby programmer
然后我们使用模块名称
and then we use the module name
在这种情况下服务
which is serving in this case
和函数 hello 的名称
and the name of the function hello
然后我们就传给它长生不老药
and then we'll just pass it elixir
所以定义模块
so defining modules
和功能
and functions
然后打电话给那些
and then calling those
模块上的功能非常简单
functions on the modules is pretty straightforward
明显地
obviously
接下来我们要做的是运行我们的代码
the next thing we want to do is to run our code
并做到这一点
and to do that
我们需要编译我们的 elixir 文件
we're going to need to compile our elixir files
骑自行车代码
to bike code
然后在 up 虚拟机上运行该自行车代码
and then run that bike code on the up virtual machine
现在早期的虚拟机好像20岁了
now the early virtual machine is like 20 years old
所以你可以想象我们将要做什么
so you can imagine what we're going to have to
经过
go through
只是为了将 hello elixir 打印到控制台
just to print out hello elixir to the console
使文件交叉编译器
make files cross compilers
好消息是一旦我们克服了这一点
the good news is once we get past this point
从这里开始走下坡路
it's all downhill from here
只是在开玩笑
just kidding
elixir 让运行我们的代码变得非常容易
elixir makes it really easy to run our code
所以运行 elixir 文件的第一种方法是使用
so the first way to run an elixir file is using the
灵药命令
elixir command
和我们的塞尔维亚
and our serbia
ex 文件在 lip 目录下
ex file is down in the lip directory
所以我只是给它一个相对路径
so I just give it a relative path there
我们看到我们得到你好长生不老药不足为奇
and we see we get hello elixir no surprise
但是当你想到它时，这很酷
but this is pretty cool when you think about it
因为文件在内存中编译
because the file got compiled in memory
进入自行车代码，然后运行
into bike code and then it was run
在早期的虚拟机上
on the early virtual machine
现在我们的文件位于混合项目目录下
now our file lives in the mixed project directory under
lib 但你可以创建一个一次性的长生不老药文件
lib but you can create a one off elixir file
任何你想的地点都可以
anywhere you want
并使用electric 命令运行它
and run it using the electric command
它不必位于混合项目目录中
it doesn't have to be in a mixed project directory
就像我们在这里一样
like we have it here
但除非它是一次性文件
but unless it's a one off file
我总是把我的代码放在一个混合项目目录中
I always put my code in a mixed project directory
因为我通常
because I usually
最终有多个文件
end up with multiple files
这就是正确的方法
and that's just the proper way to do it
我也可以用崇高的方式运行它
I can also run this back in sublime
如果我做苹果 b，我已经设置好了
I've got it set up if I do apple b
我在那里得到输出，它是你好，长生不老药
I get the output there it's hello elixir
这只是设置为
and this is just set up to
在当前文件上运行 elixir 命令
run the elixir command on the current file
我将使用这种方法
and I'm going to use this approach
至少对于第一个
at least for the first
课程的一部分
part of the course
只是这样你就不必看
just so you don't have to watch
我来回切换
me switch back and forth
在命令行和编辑器之间
between the command line and the editor
这只是快速获得结果的简单方法
and it's just the easy way to get the results quickly
运行我们的应用程序的另一种方式
another way to run our app
是使用 luxor 的交互式 shell 修复
is to use a luxor's interactive shell fix
是的，这类似于 ruby 的 irb
yeah this is similar to ruby's irb
我们可以输入
and we could just type in
任何表达式并得到它的结果
any expression and get its result
所以你输入性别
so you type sex
就这样
just like that
它会评估任何表达式
and it'll evaluate any expression
难怪你也可以打电话
no surprise you can also call
任何内置模块，如字符串
any built in modules like string
和函数 reverse 例如
and the function reverse for example
但是如果我们尝试我们的调查模块会发生什么
but what happens if we try our survey module and
打个招呼
call our hello
以我的名义传递
passing in my name
好吧，它说调查你好是未定义的
well it says survey hello is undefined
模块调查不可用
the module survey is not available
那是因为默认情况下索引不知道
and that's because by default index doesn't know about
这个调查文件
this survey file
所以编译和加载它的一种方法是使用 c
so one way to compile it and load it is using the c
功能
function
然后我们只给它一个相对的字符串
then we just give it a string which is the relative
我们要运行的文件的路径
path to the file we want to run
你注意到我们马上就得到了你好长生不老药
and you notice we immediately got hello elixir
所以这个编译
so this compiled
内存中的文件，然后加载调查模块
the file in memory and then loaded the survey module
进入会话
into the session
接着
and then
模块外的任何代码都会被解释
any code that's outside of the module is interpreted
所以这个代码就在这里打印出你好长生不老药
so this code right here that prints out hello elixir
得到解释
got interpreted
这就是为什么我们在这里看到输出
which is why we see the output right here
摆脱
to get out of
如果你能点击控制 c
if you can hit control c
这将打开刹车菜单
and this is going to open up the brake menu
然后你可以输入一个
and then you can either type a
就在这里退出本次会议
right here to get out of this session
或者像大多数人一样
or as most people do
你只是再次点击控制c
you just hit control c again
所以如果它基本上是两个控制 cs 就退出
so to get out of if it's basically two control cs
有一个开始修复的捷径和
there's a shortcut to starting fix and
加载文件
loading up a file
你可以使用它然后给它
you can just use it and then give it
文件相对路径的名称
the name of the file relative path
再次作为论据
again as an argument
文件再次在内存中编译
and again the file is compiled in memory
并加载系列模块
and the series modules is loaded
进入运行时，然后
into the runtime and then
模块外的任何代码都会被解释
any code that's outside of the module is interpreted
这就是为什么我们在这里看到这个
which is why we see this right here
所以这是一个捷径
so that's a shortcut to
开六然后用c函数编译
opening six and then using the c function to compile it
并摆脱这个
and to get out of this
我只是要击中控制 c 两次
I'm just going to hit control c twice
一场决赛
one final
在六中运行代码的方法是启动 ix 会话
way to run code in six is to start the ix session with
作为选项，然后混合
a s option and then mix
然后它说它编译了文件
and then it says it compiled the file
我们得到了输出
we got the output
因为它在这里再次解释了这条线
because it interpreted this line up here again
当您使用 dash s mix 选项启动它时
when you start it with the dash s mix option
它知道这个项目，所以
it knows about the project so
我们正在参加 ix 会议
we're in an ix session
在我们的应用程序中
in the context of our application
所以我们可以继续使用我们的模块调查
so we can go ahead and use our module survey
你好，例如
hello for example
我倾向于使用这种方法
I tend to use this approach
因为
because
它编译并加载项目中的所有模块
it compiled and loads all the modules in the project
我们可以与任何应用程序代码进行交互
and we can interact with any of the application code
所以你不必编译它或
so you don't have to compile it or
使用特定文件加载项目
load item with a specific file
您可以在这里获得所需的一切
you've got access to everything you need right here
所以让我们看看当我们需要重新编译时会发生什么
so let's look at what happens when we need to recompile
假设我们将代码从 hello 更改为 howdy
let's say we change our code from hello to howdy
如果我把它保存在这里
if I save that away here
在崇高的我可以再次击中appleby
in sublime I can hit appleby again
我们回来了，你好，长生不老药
we get back howdy elixir
在这里
down here
如果我还在 ix 会话中，我可以使用 r 函数
if I'm still in an ix session I can use the r function
然后给它一个模块的名称
and then give it the name of a module
在这种情况下，我们的模块是
in this case our module is see
并且重新编译并重新加载给定的模块
and that recompile and reloads the given module
你看我们在这里得到一点警告说
you see we get a little bit of warning here saying
我们正在重新定义该模块
we're redefining that module
然后它重新编译重新加载它
and then it recompiled reloaded it
我们看到我们有
and we see that we've got
你好，长生不老药因为它再次解释了那句话
howdy elixir because it interpreted that line again
所以现在如果我们说低麦克风它说你好麦克风
so now if we say low mic it says howdy mic
所以我要继续评论这个
so I'm going to go ahead and comment out this
就在这里线
line right here
所以它不会被解释
so it doesn't get interpreted
每次我们加载我们的项目和 ix 前进
every time we load up our project and ix going forward
所以现在我们有了一个项目和一个起点
so now we have a project and a jumping off point
从中构建我们的网络
from which to build our web
服务器接下来我们将处理我们的第一个 http 请求
server next up we'll handle our first http request